本字幕由 ShinY 深影字幕组 原创翻译制作
深影字幕组论坛地址 http://shinybbs.com
翻译： 日月 魔法莉露姆 JoJo 勒乐 红鼻子的UFO 小白
校对： 小妖怪   后期： Pilar   时间轴： Nothing
彼岸是天堂 第二季 第三集
妈妈 她快跟你一样漂亮了
Oh, Mama! She's almost as beautiful as you!
但是你看? 她穿着内衣就出来了
But see? She comes to us only in her underclothes.
我们得给她置办一身行头
We must attend to her wardrobe.
那我们要带她去女装部吗?
Are we to take her to Ladieswear, then?
多么好的想法
What a splendid notion!
她值得拥有最好的
She deserves nothing but the best.
尽管奥德丽小姐离开了 我仍然相信
And I am confident that despite Miss Audrey's departure,
她的部门仍然是无以伦比的
her department will remain the jewel in the crown.
德妮丝 你不这样认为吗?
Do you not think, Denise?
不 夫人 我也这样认为
Yes, Ma'am. I hope so.
克莱拉 你很不同
You are quite the anomaly, Clara.
你没有像别的姑娘一样吃惊而渴望
You do not gasp and wonder with the rest of your sex.
先生 想让我吃惊可不是一个玩具就能做到的
Oh, it would take more than a toy to make me gasp, sir.
有这么被宠的孩子吗?
Was ever a child so adored?
有这么被溺爱的孩子吗?
Was ever a child so spoiled?
整个小衣柜里都是女装部的衣服
An entire wardrobe in miniature ordered from Ladieswear?
真可笑
What a farce!
如果你要申请奥德丽小姐的岗位
You might want to revise that opinion
你或许要再斟酌一下你的话
if you're to apply for Miss Audrey's post.
鉴于这是芙罗拉父母的店
Seeing as Flora's parents own the store.
谁说我在申请?
Who said I was applying for anything?
海湾的沃尔特 他设了赌局
Walter. In the bays. He was offering odds.
一赔六赌你赢 一赔四赌德妮丝
Six to one for you, four to one on Denise.
他们在拿我们打赌吗?
They're betting on us?
我听见时也很震惊
I was scandalised when I heard.
谁在乎这个
Who cares about that?!
我在乎的是 出游的事怎么样了?
What I want to know is, what about the works outing?
去年莫里先生离开的时候我们错过了
We missed it last year when Mr Moray was away, so it stands to reason
按理说 今年我们应得双份快乐
we're due a double helping of pleasure this year.
你怎么好意思啊?
How do you even do that?
你就像天生就是个汗涔涔的荡妇
It's like you were born sweating smut.
我听说是要去看年度的蜡像
I heard it was the waxworks one year.
我迫不及待想看看蜡像了
Oh, I'd die to see the waxworks!
注: 基尼为英国古式货币
他们可能在三冠酒店的酒吧后面放十基尼
They could put ten guinea behind the bar of the Three Crowns
我会非常开心的
and I'd be happy.
如果真要出游
As it so happens,
我相信我对莫里的计划已有所了解
I believe I have a notion of Moray's plans.
哦 音乐厅
Oh, the Music Hall!
去年员工们被迫放弃了出游
Last year the staff had to forego their outing.
今年我们要补偿他们
This year, we shall make it up to them.
如果你确信音乐厅是最好的选择
If you're sure the Music Hall is the right choice.
达德利 只有一个星期了
One week only, Dudley.
要是错过我们就是傻子了
We'd be fools to miss it.
我的意思是 舆论确实不利于我们
I mean, the tone does tend towards the improper.
达德利 每天为员工提供食物的女人
Dudley, the staff are daily served food by a woman who cannot
连往盘子里放布丁的时候都要冷嘲热讽几句
put a pudding on a plate without innuendo.
跟梅尔托生活在一起之后 我怀疑
After life with Myrtle, I doubt any of us
我们每个人都学会了冒犯
have sensibilities left to offend.
如果奥德丽小姐仍跟我们一起
You'd never have dared suggest
你是不敢提意见的
it if Miss Audrey was still with us!
但是她没有 达德利 她没有
But she's not, Dudley! She's not.
提前关门让员工们出游?
Close early for a staff outing?
不可能
Out of the question!
我们的利润这么低 我真为你的想法感到吃惊
With profits so low, I'm surprised you even think to suggest it.
礼貌来说 利润在上涨
With respect, profits are rising.
况且年度出游并不是纯粹的放纵
And the annual outing is not a mere indulgence.
每一名员工都是我们的财富
Every member of our staff is an asset.
我们已经花时间和精力来训练他们 教育他们
It has taken time and care to train them, to teach them.
如果他们离开我们
If they leave us,
我们失去的不只是同事
we lose not just the colleague,
还有我们对他们的投资
but the investment we've made in them.
我们发的工资并不能跟工厂相提并论
We cannot compete with the wages offered by industry
所以我们必须用其他的方式
so we must work in other ways
让我们成为特别的雇主
to make ourselves the employer of choice.
- "必须"? - 这是我们一直...
- "Must"? - Well, this is something we've always...
真是胡说
Oh, God's blood, man!
你随口说的"我们" 好像你是皇室一样
You bandy about that "we" as if you were royalty!
根本就没有"我们" 这里只有我和我的妻子
There is no "we". There is only myself and my wife.
还有你 我们的雇员
And you. Our employee.
至于音乐厅 莫里 真是非常粗俗
And the Music Hall, Moray! It is fearfully vulgar, you know.
寻找新的女装部主管进展的怎么样了?
How goes the search for a new Head of Ladieswear?
已经有几人递交了申请
Several applications have already been submitted.
过程必须如此正式吗?
Must the process be so formal?
难道我们不能简单地指定一个部门里的人吗?
Can't we simply appoint one of the girls already in the department?
例如克莱拉
Clara, for example.
说真的 亲爱的 我们不能简单地提升任何
Really, darling, we can't simply promote every female
你感兴趣的女人
that catches your eye.
整个店都会归这个无礼的深色头发女人经营
the entire store would be run by pert brunettes!
想想 刚烫伤的手指
And one might imagine that fingers so recently burnt
还是会感到疼痛的
would still be smarting.
此外 要说有谁已证明了自己值得晋升的话
Besides, if anyone has proved themselves deserving
难道不是德妮丝吗?
of the advancement, surely it is Denise?
既然我们已经登了广告 我们必须按规则来
As we have advertised the post, we must follow protocol.
我可以建议本周末安排第一次面试吗?
May I suggest the first interviews at the end of the week?
务必安排 按正规程序来
By all means. Let due process be observed.
希望最优秀的人能赢
And may the best man win.
绅士们
Gentlemen.
我有种不安的感觉 我正被卷入一场战争
I have the disquieting sensation I'm caught up in a war,
战争的起因和目的只能自己猜测
the causes and objectives of which, I can only guess at.
达德利 这才是炮灰的含义
I believe, Dudley, that is the definition of cannon fodder.
女士 对不起
I'm sorry, Madam.
只有员工才有资格调整展示的衣服
Only members of staff are allowed to adjust the displays.
是不是有什么需要我帮忙的...?
But if there's anything I can help you with...?
快点 跟着她
Quick! Go after her!
看看她会不会从办公室拿表格来填
See if she picks up an application form from the office.
- 克莱拉... - 别说
- Clara... - Oh, don't.
我知道你要说什么
I know what you're going to say.
我们中的任何一人都比她那样的人强?
Better one of us, never mind which, than someone like her?
恐怕如果要我在你和
Well, I'm afraid if it came to a choice between you
鼻子下面有股怪味的丑老太婆
and some crone with a bad smell under her nose
或者嘴撅起来像猫屁股的人之间选择
and a mouth pursed up like a cat's arse,
我仍会选她
I'd still pick her.
因为 说实话
Because the truth is,
我受不了人们总选你而不选我了
I cannot bear to have you chosen over me again.
如果你觉得你跟我想法不一样
And if you believe you'd feel differently,
那你根本就没有了解你自己
you don't even begin to know yourself.
德妮丝 我刚刚在街上看到一只松鸡
Denise? I've just seen a jay in the street.
朝河边飞去了
Flying towards the river.
我现在要休息一会 现在没什么事
I'll take my break now, while it's quiet.
德妮丝什么时候对小鸟感兴趣了
Since when did Denise care for birds?
噢 别自欺欺人了
Oh, don't perjure yourself!
还有什么比真爱更令人无法忍受的吗?
Was there ever anything as insufferable as true love?
德妮丝
Denise...
有时 我觉得当我死的时候 这就是我的天堂
Sometimes, I think that when I am dead, this will be heaven.
我走向这座桥 你站在这里 等着我
Me, walking toward this bridge, you standing here, waiting.
你的想法总是很伤感 我经常注意到
You have a maudlin cast of mind. I've often noted it.
你还注意到什么?
And what else have you noted?
你还没有递交女装部主管的申请
That you have not yet submitted an application for Head of Ladieswear.
我还没腾出时间
I've not yet had time.
别交
Don't.
凯瑟琳和她丈夫之间有矛盾
There is trouble between Katherine and her husband.
他想克莱拉担任这个位置
He favours Clara for the position.
因为他喜欢克莱拉 凯瑟琳支持你
And because he favours Clara, Katherine champions you.
你们都是他们游戏中的棋子
You're both pawns in their game.
这件事不安全
That is not a safe thing to be.
你会跟克莱拉谈吗?
Will you be talking to Clara?
你会告诉她不要去申请?
Will you tell HER not to apply?
我又不爱克莱拉
I do not love Clara!
德妮丝 你自己也说了 我们必须小心行事
Denise, you said so yourself, we must tread carefully.
我们所有的努力都是要赢回天堂百货
All of our efforts must go to winning back The Paradise.
如果奥德丽小姐没有离开
If Miss Audrey had not left, if...
事情可能就不同了
things might have been different...
但是现在她离开了
But now that she has,
我无法压制在我心中慢慢苏醒的欲望
I cannot quiet this hunger that has awoken in me.
约翰 我有激情 我急切地想得到这个职位
I have such a passion, John! I burn to take this position.
一想到我必须靠边站 甚至不去尝试...
The thought that I must stand aside, not even try...
你从没有过极度渴望的东西吗?
Have you never longed for something so desperately?
除了它你什么都不想?
you could think of nothing else?
有 就是你
Yes! You.
甜心 等待实在是太难熬了
Sweetheart, is it really so hard to wait,
一年 或许几个月 天堂百货就是我们的了
when in a year, maybe months. The Paradise will be ours.
不仅会是女装部 所有的一切
Not just Ladieswear. Everything.
再叫我一遍这个名字 它会让我踏实点
Call me that name again. It will keep me steady.
甜心
Sweetheart.
你从巴黎远道而来 所以我必须教教你英语
You have come all the way from Paris, so I must teach you English.
既然那样 你得先提升自己的水平
In that case, you must improve your own.
洋娃娃不是过来 而是被带来的
The doll has not come, but been brought.
是的 爸爸
Yes, Papa.
芙罗拉 巴黎在哪?
Where is Paris, Flora?
在法国
In France.
那法国在哪?
And where is France?
海那边
Across the sea.
什么海?
Which sea?
是...
The...
...大西洋
..Atlantic.
你把法国跟美国搞混了
You confuse France with America.
不过也情有可原 都是发生革命的国家
Perhaps it's understandable - all those revolutions.
谁发现的美洲?
Who discovered America?
- 克里斯多弗・哥伦布 - 什么时候?
- Christopher Columbus.- When?
很久以前
A long time ago.
啊是啊 我也这么觉得
Oh, yes. I should think it was.
很久很久以前
A very long time ago.
久的让人不可思议
A fearfully long time ago.
1066年吗?
1066?
哦 天哪!
Well, heavens!
你这么看着她
How can anyone be expected to remember anything
谁能想起来那么多事啊?
when you look at them so?
要是当年你爸爸在婚礼上这么对我这么凶
I'm sure if your Papa had been so fierce with me at the altar,
我肯定连自己名字都想不起来了
I should have forgotten my own name.
晚安 亲爱的
Good night, my darling.
晚安 妈妈 晚安 父亲
Good night, Mama. Good night, Father.
她无知得可悲
Her ignorance is deplorable.
已经很晚了 她累了
It is late. She is tired.
你又这么严厉
And you were so stern.
是因为你背痛吗?
Is it your back?
是不是因为这个烦?
Does it trouble you?
我可以让佣人们退下 只剩你我二人
I could send the servants away...wait upon you myself.
我烦的不是背痛 凯瑟琳
It is not my wounds that gall me, Katherine.
今天在天堂百货 你怎么敢那样对我说话?
Today in The Paradise, how dare you speak to me as you did?
我? 我冒犯你了吗?!
I? I have offended?!
我们已经说好了
We had an agreement.
你非要跟莫里斗我也不拦着你
Lock horns with Moray if you must,
但你别想打垮他
but you will not seek to crush him,
你也别满世界炫耀你的轻率之举
and you will not flaunt your indiscretions for the world to see.
你当我是你的玩偶吗?!
You imagine me your puppet?!
你以为我看不出你的小算盘吗?
Do you think I don't see how you scheme and manoeuvre?
你的眼睛一直盯着某个人不放
How your eyes never leave one person?
我说过了 他对我来说什么都不是
I have told you...he is nothing to me.
哦 你关注的并不是莫里
Oh, it is not Moray your eyes follow.
而是德妮丝
It is Denise.
而且 你不是因为爱才关注她
And it is not love that draws you on,
而是因为一些恶毒之事
but something noxious.
你想惩罚她
You wish to punish her.
为什么?
Why?
因为莫里选她没选你吗?
Because he chose her over you?
你看她的眼神就像猫凶狠的看着小鸟一样
Oh, you watch her as a cat watches a bird,
你伺机待发
hoping that circumstance will present you
企图反咬她一口 同时
with an opportunity to pounce. And in the meantime,
你看似为她着想
you work for her advancement,
那是因为她职位升得越高 将来也会跌的越重
because the higher she is raised, the further she will have to fall.
你胡说八道!
You are ridiculous!
不管你维护德妮丝利益的出发点是什么
Whatever your purpose in promoting Denise's interests,
我警告你
I promise you,
如果你下次还敢在其他人面前羞辱我的话
if you ever again seek to humiliate me before other men...
哦 相信我 我从来没想那么做
Oh, believe me, I make no effort on that front.
你是自取其辱
You do the job so thoroughly yourself.
抱歉
I am sorry.
我累了
I am tired.
我一直在想芙罗拉
I've been thinking about Flora.
我没想到她会那么无知
Her ignorance appals me.
我该雇个女家庭教师了
I intend to engage a governess.
然后把阁楼改造成书房
The attic will be converted to a schoolroom.
今后不会再让她懒散 放纵
An end to idleness and indulgence.
也不许购物 玩洋娃娃了
To shopping and dolls.
没有出游?! 没有出游?!
No outing? No outing?!
我相信威斯顿先生认为在当前形势下...
I believe that Mr Weston feels that in the current climate...
当前形势算个屁!
Current climate be buggered!
他以为我多久才能享受一次这种待遇?
How often does he think I get to savour a treat like that?
一年只有一天 仅有这一天才能做我自己
One sole and solitary day a year to take my place in the world
才能像淑女一样享受闲暇!
and enjoy my leisure like a lady!
我有个披肩还准备穿呢!
I have a tippet I was to wear!
为什么会这样 达德利先生?
What was it to have to been, Mr Dudley?
是因为音乐厅 对吗?
Was it the Music Hall? Was it?
我不知道
I cannot say.
莫里本来要带我们去音乐厅的
Moray would have took us to the Music Hall,
而那个可恶的混球不准!
and that miserable bugger has forbade him!
我发誓要让他为此付出代价
Oh, I swear I will make him pay for this.
我要把他的心挖出来
I will cut out his heart
放盘子里 然后端上桌!
and serve it up on a platter!
记得提醒我去三冠酒店吃饭啊!
Remind me to start taking my meals at the Three Crowns!
德妮丝 我一直在考虑
Denise, I've been thinking about
你申请接替奥德丽小姐职位的事
your application for Miss Audrey's job...
- 山姆 - 我突然想到
- Sam... - Now, it strikes me
有一点她有你没有...
that the one thing she had that you do not...
- 山姆! - 是一句座右铭
- Sam! - ...is a motto.
山姆 我不申请了
Sam, I've decided not to apply.
不申请了?!
Not to apply?!
如果有人天生适合接替奥德丽小姐的位置
If anyone was born to fill Miss Audrey's shoes,
那就是你啊!
it is you!
你会毁了沃尔特的赔率!
You'll cause havoc with Walter's odds.
他必须得把梅尔托的赔率从一赔五百调整到
He'll have to move Myrtle from 500 to one,
四百九十九赔五百了!
to 499!
五百！他娘的一赔五百?
500! 500 to bloody one?
你知道吗 我绞尽脑汁也想不出
You know, I've been racking me brains why you might choose
你为什么不申请做女装部主管
not to apply for Head of Ladieswear.
我只能想到一个原因
And there's only one thing I can think of.
你怀孕了吗?
Are you in trouble?
因为如果是这样 德妮丝 你要让他帮助你
Because if you are, you have to make him stand by you, Denise.
让他负责!
Hold him to his promises!
你要是不跟他说我可以替你说...
I'll talk to him if you can't do...
不！克莱拉 不是那样的
No! Clara. No. It's not that.
情况很复杂 但不是你想的那回事
It's complicated, but it's not that.
好吧 虽然你不打算说
Well. I would ask,
但我还是要问 到底是不是?
but you're not going to say. Are you?
如果我得到了那个工作
Look, I won't change anything, you know.
我不会做任何改变 任何
If it's me that gets the job. Not a thing.
但是在这儿我们可以做的事很多!
But there's so much more we could do here!
可以把它变成一个独一无二的部门!
This could be a department like no other.
一个前所未有的商店!
A store no one's ever been to before.
甚至不再是一个商店
Not even a shop any more,
它会是一个... 梦幻的世界
it could be a... a fantasy.
这不是生活 德妮丝 这是工作 仅仅是工作
This isn't life, Denise, it's work, only work.
他们怎么看这事?
How did they take it?
他们大部分人... 很失望
Most of them ... disappointed.
梅尔托... 快气疯了
Myrtle...murderous.
威斯顿!
Weston!
他借我之手惩罚他们
He punishes them through me.
不 他借他们之手惩罚你
No. He punishes you through them.
他是一个能发现人的弱点
He is a man who sees where the tender places are
然后有的放矢的家伙
and lands the blow accordingly.
抱歉打扰一下 莫里先生
I'm sorry to interrupt, Mr Moray, sir,
我能和你谈谈吗?
might I have a moment of your time?
我会在办公室
I will be in the office.
德妮丝
Denise.
再跟我说一遍
Tell me again
如果天堂百货是我们的 会怎么样!
what it will be like when The Paradise is ours!
再跟我说一遍我为何要袖手旁观!
Tell me again why I must stand aside.
发生什么事了?
What's happened?
克莱拉是...
Clara is...
... 我的朋友
..my friend.
但对她来说 女装部主管只是一份工作
But to her, Head of Ladieswear is only a job.
而对我来说
To me,
它却是我得以成长 呼吸 生存的机会!
it would be a chance to grow, to breathe, to live!
它...
It...
...会...
..will...
是...
be...
...值得的
..worth it.
我们在赌的是更重要的事
We are playing for bigger stakes.
我们必须把次要的想法放一边
We must set aside lesser considerations.
次要的想法?!
Lesser considerations?!
这只是一个部门
It's only one department.
另外 这次晋升并不在我们的利益范围内
Besides, perhaps this advancement would not have been in our interests.
如果像你认为的那样
If, as you believe,
凯瑟琳不会像她假装的那样
Katherine is not as accepting of the situation
接受我们的处境 那么你任何的失误
of us, as she would pretend, any failure on your part
只会被她用作对抗我们的武器
would only give her ammunition to use against us.
你觉得我会失败?!
You imagine I would fail?!
每个人都会失败!
Everyone fails!
只有犯错我们才能成长!
That is how we learn! By making mistakes.
大多数人都默默成长 你不需要大肆宣扬
Most of us do so privately. You would not have that luxury.
你太容易被看穿 太容易被人了解了
You are too visible, too known.
我俩的关系已经是众所周知的秘密了
Your association with me is a public secret.
从你选择的那一刻起
You would be scrutinised and judged from the moment
你就注定会被大众审视 评价
you took on the role.
失败 错误...
Failure, mistakes...
你认为我没能力接替奥德丽小姐的位置吗?
Do you even believe me capable of filling Miss Audrey's shoes?!
你是我的小冠军 但这次可是大动作
I think you are my little champion, but this is a big step up.
别老是用对孩子的口气和我说话!
Do not speak to me as if I am a child!
德妮丝 我们不只接受来自本城的申请
Denise, we are receiving applications not just from the city,
而是更大范围的
but beyond.
我从未发现竞争是如此激烈
I've never known competition as fierce!
没错 你让我感到很惊讶
Look, you know that you astonish me,
你的想法更让我大吃一惊
that your ideas astonish me.
可想成为女装部主管要的可不仅是想法
But being Head of Ladieswear requires more than ideas.
放弃这场争斗吧 反正怎样都会输的
You are bowing out of a fight you may have lost anyway.
为之如此牺牲真的值吗?
Is that really such a sacrifice?
对我来说值!
It is to me!
我想申请
I would like to make an application
女装部主管这个职位
for the position of Head of Ladieswear.
德妮丝! 我以为你已经改变主意了
Denise! I thought you'd changed your mind.
我又改回来了
I've changed it back again.
如你们所知 我们这整个星期
As you know, we have, all week,
都不断收到来竞争奥德丽小姐空职的申请
been taking applications for the post vacated by Miss Audrey.
你们应该把我这话当成对你们自己的赞美
You should take it as a personal compliment to yourselves that
这么多才华横溢 经验丰富的候选人
so many talented but highly experienced candidates
申请成为你们中的一员
have applied to join your number.
现在申请已递交完毕
All submissions are now in
我们将从中制定一份决选名单
and we'll presently be drawing up a short list.
被选中的候选人
Successful candidates
将被邀至天堂百货参加面试 谢谢
will be invited to The Paradise for interview. Thank you.
这两人就是脖子扭断了也不愿看对方一眼
Those two are going to give themselves neck strain not looking at each other.
伙计们 来下注吧
Right then, lads, let's be having your bets.
沃尔特!
Walter!
你在开赌
You are running a book.
赌谁会被任命为女装部的主管
Odds are given on who will be appointed Head of Ladieswear.
我愿意下注
I should like to place a bet.
十先令 押梅尔托
Ten shillings. On Myrtle.
亚瑟 你也许好奇为何我要浪费这十先令
Arthur. You're wondering why I choose to throw away ten shillings.
梅尔托甚至都没申请这个职位
Myrtle hasn't even applied for the job.
沃尔特提议下注的唯一原因是因为一想到她
The only reason Walter was offering odds is because the thought
代替奥德丽小姐 大家都会笑的
of her taking over from Miss Audrey made everyone laugh so.
你认为被大家当作笑柄感觉如何?
How do you suppose it feels to be the joke that everyone gets?
那么如果是有人表态了呢?
What if there were to be a gesture made?
十个先令 是表明有人认为
Ten shillings that said he considered Myrtle
梅尔托和所有人在所有事上都平等
the equal of anything and anyone.
那会让她好受些
It would make her feel better.
但是她得要听到这个才行
But only if she heard about it.
那么 我们下一步该做什么?
So. How do we progress?
等查阅完所有申请
When all applications are read,
你们每个人都写出一个或几个
it is for each of you to put forward
你们感觉值得面试的人
the name or names of those you feel merit an interview.
四个人进入决选
We have a short list of four.
如果我们这结束了 我要去见见芙罗拉
If our business is concluded, I should see to Flora.
我该如何回应那些
How would you like me to respond to the candidates
没在名单里的候选人?
who have not been so fortunate as to make the short list?
感谢他们的参与
Thank them for their interest.
告诉他们以后再有职位
Tell them we'll be happy to consider them
我们会很乐意考虑他们的
for future positions.
弗兰克先生
Mr Franks.
为什么每次我一见到你
Why is it that, whenever I see you,
我都感觉你在看着我?
I have the impression that you're watching me?
我说过 我在看人这方面训练有素
I have told you, I have trained myself to know men.
知道一个人什么时候值得追随
To know when a man is worth the following.
同样了解历史的潮流何时改变
To also know when the tide of history is changing
并向新宠靠拢
and inclining towards a new favourite.
发现自己的用处 给这样的人效劳
To find oneself of use - of service - to such a man
将会感到十分荣幸
would be a very great privilege.
妈妈 快看!
Oh, Mama! Look!
对不起
Excuse me.
她看上去很漂亮 你也是
She looks lovely. You both do.
真抱歉 威斯顿夫人
Oh, I am sorry, Mrs Weston.
亚瑟
Arthur.
威斯顿夫人有点不适
Mrs Weston has taken faint.
请帮我把这些交给克莱拉和德妮丝
Please deliver these to Clara and Denise.
好的 先生
Yes, sir.
来 挽着我的手
Come. Take my arm.
威斯顿夫人 我无意冒犯
Mrs Weston, I do not wish to intrude
但是我不能看着你这么痛苦
but I cannot see you in such distress
而不问问是否有我能帮得上忙的地方
and not ask if there is any way in which I might help.
你是位父亲 对吗?
You are a father, are you not?
我有两个孩子
I have two children.
当我结婚时我没想到...
When I married I did not expect...
芙罗拉她...
Flora is...
我丈夫发现她简直无知得可悲
My husband finds her woefully ignorant.
或许她的确是
And perhaps she is.
但是我并不想让她被赶进书房
But I do not want her banished to the schoolroom with lessons
跟着老师上课 而没有关爱
and tutors and no love.
我不想失去她
I do not want to lose her.
我不会情愿我的孩子无知地成长
Well, I should not care for my children to be raised in ignorance.
但为什么一定要在书房里?
But why must it be in a schoolroom?
为什么你不能教她呢?
Why can you not teach her?
你是个有学问的女人
You are an accomplished woman
旅行又增长了你的见闻
and you have had the benefit of travel to broaden your mind.
我太肤浅了 我几乎都不记得了
I am so shallow, I remember almost none of it.
再好不过了
All the better.
你可以同时教芙罗拉和你自己
You can teach Flora and yourself at the same time.
如果我们自己不以身作则 我们的孩子
I cannot see how our children can be expected to acquire
就不可能如我们期望地那样热爱学习
a love of learning unless we ourselves demonstrate it.
那你是按照你的原则去做的吗?
And do you follow your own precept?
每天我翻开词典随便找一个单词
Every day I open the dictionary at random and pick out a word
并把它牢记在脑中
and commit it to memory.
虽然我在医学术语和灌木上有点偷懒
Though I discount medical terms and shrubs.
你这种对知识的渴求真让我感到羞愧
Such a thirst for knowledge. You quite put me to shame.
有一天 我们还年轻时
One day, when we were young,
莫里用了一个我不懂的词
Moray used a word I did not understand.
我意识到如果我不努力 像他一样渴求进步
I realised that if I did not try and match his hunger for betterment,
那么他将遥遥领先 我就再也无法追上他了
then he would get so far ahead of me I would never catch him again.
我也不想失去他
I did not want to lose him.
你不要感觉是你一个人在努力
You need not feel alone in your efforts.
如果你能考虑让芙罗拉走出你的视线一阵子
If you would consider allowing Flora out of your sight for a time,
那么天堂百货的生意对她就是一种教育
then the business of The Paradise can be an education in itself.
并且我认为现在我该有个初学者来协助我了
And I believe it is high time I had a junior to assist me.
山姆!
Sam!
你在决选名单上!
You made the short list!
还有克莱拉和另外两个人
And Clara. And two others.
还有那嘴巴像猫屁股一样的女人
Including her with a mouth like a cat's arse.
我看大家都被梅尔托的"文雅"给传染啦
I see Myrtle's refinement is rubbing off on all of us!
- 什么时候面试? - 明天
- When are the interviews? - Tomorrow.
山姆 你说的奥德丽小姐有
Sam, what did you mean
但我没有的是句座右铭是什么意思?
when you said the only thing Miss Audrey had that I don't is a motto?
不只是奥德丽小姐
Not just Miss Audrey.
这座大楼里每个部门的主管
Every Head of Department in this building
都有条标志性的座右铭
has a signature saying.
奥德丽小姐的座右铭是
With Miss Audrey it was,
呃 灵感总是在晚上到来
er, things came to her in the night.
玻璃制品部的爱德华先生则一直都在声明
Mr Edwards in Glassware is for ever declaring,
"水晶上的污点就是我们部门的污点"
"A smudge on the crystal is a slur on the department."
海湾的沃尔特是...
With Walter in the bays, it's...
- "我知道你做了什么" - 我知道你做了什么
- "I can see what you're doing." -  I can see what you're doing.
你不能没有座右铭 德妮丝
You cannot be without one, Denise.
我冒昧地写了几句不错的
Now, I took the liberty of setting down a few possibilities.
"姑娘们 姑娘们 姑娘们
"Girls. Girls. Girls.
姑娘们 姑娘们"
Girls. Girls."
我喜欢这个词 还有你念它的方式
I like the word. I like the way you say it.
也许更多的是个人意见 那一条
Perhaps more of a personal treat, that one.
"当一天结束 我们的工作结束"
"When the day is done, so are we."
以防懒惰
In case of idleness.
"在皮布尔斯有句老话"
"We have a saying in Peebles."
皮布尔斯: 英国苏格兰中部古国
最妙的是你可以把它用在员工和顾客两者上
Ah, now, the genius of that one is you can use it on staff and customers alike.
反正又没人知道在皮布尔斯有什么话
Well, since no-one has any notion of what is said in Peebles,
你可以任意加上你喜欢的话
you can append it to whatever you like.
你自己的想法 说出来就像谚语一样权威
Your own thoughts, delivered with all the authority of a proverb.
"在皮布尔斯有句老话"
"We have a saying in Peebles."
噢 梅尔托 难道这事儿不能私下里整理吗?
Oh, Myrtle, is that not something the three of you could arrange in private?
山姆对本季的露胸装没有概念
Sam has no notion of this season's decollete.
好了
There.
恭喜你!德妮丝!
Congratulations, Denise!
谢谢 亚瑟
Thank you, Arthur.
虽然 乔纳斯先生会不高兴的
Though, er, Mr Jonas shouldn't be pleased.
你们没听说吗? 大家都在谈论这个呢
Haven't you heard? Everyone's talking about it.
他押十个先令赌梅尔托会得到这份工作
He put ten shillings on Myrtle to get the job.
一赔五百
At 500-1.
那个?
That one?
- 荷兰语 - 这个?
- Dutch. - This?
西班牙语
Spanish.
那边的呢
Over yonder?
意大利语 像西班牙语 但更像意语
Italian! Like the Spanish, but with more Is.
芙罗拉 你太惊人了
Flora, you are a marvel.
仅用了一个上午你就能分辨欧洲所有的语言了
In one morning you have managed to identify every European language
甚至一些更远地方的
and a few from further afield.
现在 这些从日本来的箱子对我们非常重要
Now, the crates from Japan are particularly precious to us at this time.
你觉得是为什么
Why do you suppose that is?
日本的玩意儿很流行?
Japanese items are popular?
是的
They are.
会断货吗?
Is there a shortage?
恐怕有 这又是为什么?
We fear one. And why might that be?
发生了一场大灾难
There has been a great disaster.
他们的海军在风暴中沉没了
Their navy was sunk in a storm
所以现在他们不能运送他们做的东西
and now they are unable to deliver the goods they have made.
呃 那应该是场特大风暴
Well, that would have to be a mighty storm indeed.
不过你能联想到灾难上还不错
But you are right to think in terms of disaster.
只是这种灾难是人为的
Only this one was man-made.
战争!
A war!
酝酿中的战争 战争摧毁贸易和生命 看吧?
A war brewing. And war destroys trade as well as lives. See?
通过逻辑推理
Through logical deduction,
你慢慢地掌握了一些世界知识了
you have come to a grasp of world affairs.
累么? 好极了
Tired? Very well, then.
有些人我想让你见一见
There are some people I should like you to meet.
四码半的三乘六大小最好的亚麻布
Four and a half yards of finest cambric at three and six
卖十五先令九便士
makes 15 shillings and ninepence.
加上罗缎丝带值十六先令整
Add the grosgrain ribbon, we'll call it an even 16.
- 那么丝带花费多少? - 三便士?
- Which means the ribbon costs? - Thruppence?
女士们先生们
Ladies and gentlemen,
这是我的新助手 芙罗拉・威斯顿小姐
my new assistant, Miss Flora Weston.
你怎么算得这么快?
How do you do it so fast?
山姆比任何人都熟悉乘法表
Sam knows his times tables like no-one else.
这可不容易
It's not easy.
比方说 七七表就非常之难
The seven times table, for example, is the very devil.
正常人可记不住它
No sane person can learn it,
你必须巧妙地将它放在脑中
you have to keep it in your head with tricks.
不过九九表... 现在有种九九表
Nines, on the other hand... Now, there's a pattern with nines.
- 按钮(法语)!- 是的!
- Bouton! - Yes!
- 手套!(法语) - 非常好!
- Gant! - Very good!
雨伞(法语)
Parapluie.
芙罗拉纠正了达德利的发音
Parapluie才对
Parapluie.
因为Pluie是雨的意思
Because pluie is rain.
我今天学了好多
I have learned so many things today,
我都不知道怎么把它们装进脑子里
I don't know how they will fit inside my head.
大脑的空间比你想象地要大得多
There's more room in there than you think.
你可能会忘记一些
Some items may fall out,
不过绝大多数都会留在你的脑中
but most'll find a place to lodge.
芙罗拉小姐
Miss Flora.
恶毒是什么意思?
What does noxious mean?
怎么 那是另一种有害的说法
Why, it's another way of saying harmful.
我不知道人们怎么说梅尔托的厨艺
I don't know what people have been saying about Myrtle's cooking,
不过我可以跟你保证 她做得蛋糕美味极了
but I can assure you, her cake is excellent.
有害的? 妈妈为什么想害德妮丝?
Harmful? Why would Mama wish to harm Denise?
爸爸说这就是为什么妈妈总盯着德妮丝
Papa says that is why Mama watches her all the time,
不过我想他一定错了
but I think he must be confused.
我觉得妈妈整天看着她是因为她太美了
I think Mama watches her all the time because she is so pretty.
那孩子听到了些什么
The child overheard something.
她就是一个孩子
She is a child.
她不能肯定什么 我们也不行
She cannot be sure what was meant, nor can we.
不管这意味着什么
Whatever the meaning,
非常明显威斯顿女士对德妮丝保有恶意
it is clear that Mrs Weston bears some manner of ill-will towards Denise,
而她却支持她成为女装部的主管
and yet she advocates her for Head of Ladieswear.
这种矛盾让我感到恐慌
There is a paradox in that which unnerves me.
我对威斯顿夫人没有敌意
I am no enemy to Mrs Weston,
但德妮丝是我的朋友
but Denise is my friend.
我关心她 而现在... 我担心她
I care for her and now... I fear for her.
你以为我不担心吗?
You think I don't?
我是觉得你不在的时候
I think you did not see her as I did
你没有像我一样每天看着她
every day of your absence
看她一个人 面对流言蜚语
alone, exposed to gossip and rumour
还有丑闻的猜忌
and the speculation of scandalmongers,
身边没有她爱的人
without the man she loves,
她没有办法与任何人分享她的感受
unable to share the feelings of her heart with anyone.
被盯住 被指戳 被说闲话
Stared at and pointed at and whispered about.
尽管如此
And yet through it all,
她却总是抬起头熟练地礼貌地优雅地完成工作
she held her head up and did her job with skill and courtesy and grace,
即使有段时间支撑住她的仅仅是她强烈的意志
even though there were days when I could see the only thing holding her together was her own force of will.
我从没有这么尊敬过一个人
I've never held anyone in higher esteem.
即使是你 莫里
Not even you, Moray.
德妮丝很勇敢很机智
Denise is gallant and resourceful.
但这并不代表她不会受伤害
But she's not invulnerable.
你曾劝她退出这场争斗
You persuaded her once to withdraw from the fray.
不能再做一次吗?
Could you not do so again?
我怕德妮丝不愿意再听我的了
I fear Denise is no longer minded to listen to me.
你必须让她听你的
Then you must make her.
我太愚蠢无知了
I am disgracefully ignorant
我再也不能忍了
and I simply cannot tolerate it any longer.
我决定自学
I am determined to educate myself.
哦 我看到了法国选举
Oh, I see there are elections in France.
小姐你对政治有兴趣吗?
Do you take an interest in politics Mademoiselle?
没有? 那你可能想知道
No? Then perhaps you would care to know that
威尔士王子在苏格兰枪击
the Prince Of Wales is shooting in Scotland
还有下议院准备讨论日本问题
and the House Of Commons is to debate the Japanese question.
那你觉得会讨论什么问题呢
Now, what do you suppose that is
还有他们为什么要讨论这个问题?
and why do you suppose they're debating it?
我想可能和日本正在酝酿的战争有关
I expect it has something to do with the war brewing in Japan.
你对日本即将到来的战争有什么看法?
And what do you know of the impending war in Japan?
它扰乱贸易 爸爸
It disrupts trade, Papa.
我想也许这就是政府要争论的原因
I think perhaps that is why the government wish to debate it.
我曾以为你没有头脑
And I thought you empty-headed.
芙罗拉 我好像错看了你
Flora, it seems I misjudged you.
现在我脑子里装了各种各样的东西
I have all manner of things in my head now.
但达德利先生说我还能容纳更多
But Mr Dudley says there is still room for more.
达德利先生
Mr Dudley.
我享受了一整天爸爸!
I have had such a day, Papa!
我们属于天堂百货 我太高兴了
I am so glad that we belong to The Paradise.
我们不属于天堂百货 天堂百货属于我们
We do not belong to The Paradise. The Paradise belongs to us.
她只是说她觉得那里像家一样
She means only that she feels at home there.
我的女儿 觉得在店里像在家里一样?
My daughter, at home in a shop?
芙罗拉 到你房间去
Flora. Run along to your room.
玛莎会帮你准备睡觉
Martha will be wanting to get you ready for bed.
晚安 妈妈
Good night, Mama.
我想我已经把我的想法说得很清楚了
I thought I'd made my feelings clear.
天堂不是她的游乐场
The Paradise is not her playground.
但是你看看她学到了多少
But see how much she has learnt.
我不容许我的女儿看起来
I will not have my daughter smelling of that shop
像是商人的种一样
as if she were the spawn of some merchant!
也许你是对的
Perhaps you were right.
家庭教师 看来都没有必要了
A governess, tutors - it all does seem rather unnecessary.
也许我就应该直接把她送到学校去
Perhaps I should simply send her away to school.
我不允许! 你听到了吗? 我不会允许的!
I will not allow it! Do you hear me? I will not!
你竟敢命令我?!
You dare to dictate to me?!
我警告你 凯瑟琳
I warned you, Katherine,
不要指望我的修养
do not presume on my gallantry
也不要以为你是女人我就不敢怎么样
or the protection of your sex.
如果你选择和我拔剑相向
If you choose to cross swords with me,
我会让你记得你嫁的是一个士兵
I will make you remember you married a soldier.
我会迎战的 懂吗?
I will meet you head on. Yes?
可你要忍受你背上的伤
And yet you bear your scars on your back.
滚出去 滚出去!
Get out. Get out!
你在紧张明天的面试吗?
Are you nervous about your interviews tomorrow?
如果是我我会的 我会合不了眼的
I would be if I were you. I wouldn't sleep a wink.
哦 让我猜猜
Oh, let me guess.
你在去三冠酒店的路上看见了夜莺?
You saw a nightingale on the way to The Three Crowns?
或者是莫里先生办公室的花鸡?
Or was it a chaffinch in Mr Moray's office?
我很快回来
I won't be long.
好吧 如果那两个人重修旧好的话
Well, if those two are on terms again,
我可能会放弃的
I may as well give up.
而且 就一次 我觉得我有机会成功
And, just for once, I thought I might be in with a chance.
莫里先生不会就因为他喜欢德妮丝
Mr Moray wouldn't give Denise the job just
而给她这份工作的
because he likes her.
- 他不是这样的人 - 亚瑟是对的
- He's not like that. - Arthur's right.
如果他对爱情这样傻那他绝对建不起天堂百货
If he was such a fool for love he would never have built up The Paradise.
如果他不是 他永远不会失去爱
If he wasn't, he'd have never lost it.
德妮丝
Denise.
你为什么要见我?
Why did you wish to see me?
我从巴黎回来的时候 你告诉我...
When I returned from Paris, you told me that...
凯瑟琳太冷静了 太好了
Katherine was too calm, too kind.
让你害怕
That you feared her.
你这样做是对的 她想伤害你
You were right to do so. She means you harm.
如果你获得了这份工作...
If you win this role...
你觉得我没能力做那份工作
This role that you do not consider me ready for or capable of?
如果你成为了女装的总管
If you are made Head Of Ladieswear,
你会在明处 失去遮掩
you will be visible. Exposed.
而且不管凯瑟琳怎么做 我都没有办法保护你
And whatever Katherine's designs, I will not be able to shield you.
你担心你的计划会因为我而破坏?
You fear your plans will suffer through me?
不 我担心你会受伤!
No, I fear you will suffer!
直到达德利告诉我 我才意识到
I had not realised until Dudley told me
我去法国的那段日子
how my departure to France
你是怎样脆弱 没人保护
left you vulnerable, unprotected.
我无论如何也不想再让事情重演
I would not, for all the world, have that happen again.
德妮丝 求求你...
Denise, please...
让我保护你
let me keep you safe.
求求你... 退出吧
Please... withdraw.
当你是我这个年纪时
When you were my age,
你在建立天堂百货
you were building The Paradise.
是的 但你不是我
Yes, but you are not me.
- 你是你自己 - 你的小冠军
- You are yourself - Your little champion.
- 是的 - 但不是你的对手
- Yes! - But not your equal?
你是不同的
You are different.
当我是你这个年龄时 我确实在建立天堂百货
When I was your age I was building The Paradise.
但不仅仅是因为我有想法
But not only because I had the ideas,
更是因为我走进外面的世界 去求 去借
because I'd gone out into the world and begged and borrowed
战战兢兢地寻找资金上的支持
and browbeaten my way into the kind of financial backing
来让我的想法成为现实
that turns ideas into reality.
我在你身上看不到这点
That is not something I see in you.
因为如果我去银行寻找资金支持
Because if I walked into a bank seeking financial backing,
他们会以为我是去当清洁工
they would assume I'd come to sell my services as a cleaner
或是干脆把自己给买了
or perhaps just to sell myself.
我都不知道女人能不能通过那些门槛
I do not even know that a woman would be allowed through the doors.
这种不同不是我造成的
It is different for me but not because I am different
而是这世界就是如此
but because the world treats me so.
你不明白吗
Can you not see that?
我不想你变成另一个版本的我
I would not want you to become another version of what I am.
像我一样
Of who I am.
约翰...
Oh, John...
..这是我们意见相左的地方
..that is where we differ.
德妮丝
Denise.
他不明白
He cannot see.
他不明白我在各个方面都和他一样
He cannot see that I am like him in every way.
限制我的成就的并不是我的内在原因
That the limits to what I might achieve are not inside me
而是外因
but outside.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
这么晚了 你没必要听我的抱怨
It's late, you do not have to listen to my tales of woe.
我会听你告诉我的一切
I would listen to whatever you had to tell me.
我只希望向他展示我真正的才能
I only wish that I could show him what I'm truly capable of.
在莫里先生办公室的走廊上放四把椅子
Set four chairs in the corridor outside Mr Moray's office.
威斯顿夫人 你来早了
Mrs Weston. You are in advance of the schedule.
面试还没开始...
Interviews aren't set to commence until...
我想先跟你谈谈
I wanted to see you first.
真是史上最不幸的事
It is the most unfortunate thing.
芙罗拉的娃娃 似乎在生产的时候有些问题
Flora's doll. It seems there was a fault. In the manufacture.
真的很抱歉 夫人 我们当然会换新的给你
I'm sorry to hear that, ma'am. We will of course replace it.
如果你可以把有缺陷的产品给我
If you could let me have the defective item.
不
No!
它不见了 是我的错
It is gone. It is my fault.
我不想让芙罗拉看到并... 伤心
I did not wish Flora to see it and be... distressed.
我告诉她我们会再给她一个一模一样的
I have told her we will replace it with another the same,
就要一个一样的
just the same
然后就像什么也没发生过一样
and it will be as if nothing happened.
威斯顿夫人 出了什么问题吗
Mrs Weston, is something wrong?
发生了什么让你伤心的事吗
Has something happened to distress you?
谢谢你对芙罗拉的照顾
Thank you for the care you took with Flora.
我不会忘记的
I will not forget.
先生 我可以跟您谈谈吗
Sir, might I have a moment of your time.
今早我头痛欲裂
I've a devilish head on me this morning.
昨晚的事一片模糊
Last night is something of a fog.
我想不起来我怎么会
I can't remember what I was drinking,
喝这么多酒
other than too much.
祝你健康
Your health.
我能帮到你什么
How can I be of help?
我以为应该反过来讲
I was hoping it might be the other way round.
我可能会帮到您
That I may be of assistance to you.
我不觉得我需要帮助
I wasn't aware I stood in need of assistance.
是 你可能不需要
No. Quite possibly you are not.
你必须明白 天堂百货不仅仅只是个地方
You must understand... The Paradise is more than just a place.
还包括工作人员 这帮人的首领是莫里
It's a people, a tribe whose leader is Moray.
他们软弱 易受骗 并且极度忠诚
They are weak, credulous, loyal beyond measure.
他们没有看到莫里气数已尽
They do not see that Moray's time is past,
只是他对他们很好 是他们承认的领袖
only that he was good to them, their rightful king.
每个反对他的小动作
Every action against him
都会增加他们的忠诚度
increases their loyalty.
有可能 极有可能
It is possible, more than possible,
他们对这男人的愚忠
that in their ill-conceived
会使他们攻击被他们视为篡权者的人
fidelity to the man, they might turn on those they view as his usurpers.
他们如果发起内部斗争
They'd be turning on themselves in the process.
我将解雇他们所有人
I'd sack every man jack of them.
那天堂百货会怎么样呢
What would then happen to The Paradise?
那下金蛋的鹅
The goose that lays the golden eggs.
我不能容忍暴动
I will not tolerate insurrection.
我告诉您了 他们简单 容易上当
I have told you, they are simple, credulous.
我们只需要转移他们的忠诚
All that is needed is for them to transfer their loyalty.
他们现在所有的抱怨嘀咕都是围绕着
All their murmurings and mutterings at present
禁止他们组团去音乐厅的
centre around the forbidden outing to the Music Hall.
如果您找到改变现状的方法...
If you were to find a way of restoring it...
以我的经验来说 撤销禁令
In my experience, the rescinding of an order is never anything
是示弱的表现
but an exhibition of weakness.
我相信还有其他方法
I believe there is another way.
您今天早上将面试
You are this morning conducting interviews
竞选女式服装部主管的候选人 不是吗
for the Head of Ladieswear, are you not?
如果一位顾客想要一件礼服
If a customer was desirous of a gown
可你觉得不适合她
you did not think suited her,
你会怎么说
what would you say?
那要由礼服的价钱决定
That would depend on the price of the gown.
在冒昧的发表对这件事的看法之前
Before venturing an opinion on the matter,
我会先去找更有经验的领导征求意见
I would seek the advice of a more experienced authority.
先生 我觉得有些真相是女人不想听到的
Sir, I believe there are some truths a woman does not wish to hear.
我会直接告诉她
I would tell her the truth.
我不想顾客兴起才来
I do not want her custom only today,
我希望客人们成回头客
but tomorrow and for many years to come.
要做到这点 我们和顾客之间必须信任彼此
And for that, there must be a trust between us.
真心实意 让别人感受到我们对产品的自信
At the heart of it, one must have faith in one's own stock.
如果给你这个提升的机会 你会做出哪些改变
If you were given this advancement, what would you change?
一切听领导安排
Whatever I was told to.
天哪 从哪开始说呢
Heavens! Where to start?
我不会改变任何事
I wouldn't change a thing.
如果奥德丽小姐觉得够好了
If it was good enough for Miss Audrey,
那我也觉得够好了
it's good enough for me.
我会改变任何我觉得需要改变的事
I would change, anything I felt needed changing.
你介意说的更详细点吗
Would you care to be more specific?
为什么 不行
Why, no.
因为如果我告诉你了 我恐怕就升不了职了
Because then you would have my ideas and I might have no advancement.
你似乎很看重你的想法啊 洛维特小姐
You seem to set great store by your ideas,  Miss Lovett.
我不仅有想法 更会用我的能力去实现它们
Not just by my ideas, but by my ability to make them real.
洛维特小姐 最后一个问题
Miss Lovett? One last question.
我们假设 为了鼓舞士气
Let us say, that for reasons of morale,
你想带员工们去音乐厅
you wished to take the staff on a trip to the Music Hall.
再假设 由于种种原因
And let us say, that for reasons
我们不能去 你被拒绝了
we need not go into, you were denied.
你会怎么做
What would you do?
如果我不能带员工们去音乐厅 我相信
If I could not take the staff to the Music Hall, I believe
我会找方法把音乐厅带到他们面前
I would seek to bring the Music Hall to them.
如果你被告知 考虑到以防资金运转不周
And if you were told that the considerations preventing
没有任何预算
attendance were in part financial, that there was no budget
去请任何表演人员 你会怎么做
to pay for any performance, what would you do?
在皮布尔斯有句老话
We have a saying in Peebles...
"如果买不到 那就自己做"
"If the store doesnae have it, make it yirsel'."
我会这么做
That's what I would do.
我会做一个音乐厅之夜
I would make a Night at the Music Hall.
德妮丝 面试的怎么样
Oh, Denise! How did it go?
我说了 山姆 "在皮布尔斯有句老话"
I said it, Sam! "We have a saying in Peebles!"
我直视他们并脱口而出
I looked them straight in the eye and just said it!
那奖励我一个吻吧
So, does that earn me a kiss?
比吻更好 下班一起喝一杯
Better than a kiss. Drink after work.
德妮丝 某人想私下找你谈谈
Denise. There is someone who would like a word with you privately.
洛维特小姐
Miss Lovett.
令人印象深刻的面试
An impressive interview.
我对你自制音乐厅的想法特别感兴趣
I was particularly struck by your idea for the home-made Music Hall.
告诉我... 如果在现实中你要尝试这种事
Tell me... if you were to attempt such a thing in reality,
你需要什么
what would you need?
在天黑之后的大礼堂
The Great Hall. After dark.
和尽可能多的灯和蜡烛
With as many lamps and candles as we could find.
如果这活动是完全仿制
And, if the experience was to truly replicate
音乐厅之夜 那我们还需要茶点
a night at the Music Hall, there would have to be refreshments.
这些都可以安排 表演人员是谁呢
That could be arranged. Who would be your performers?
我们 天堂百货
Us! The Paradise!
非常好 那我就委托你去落实这件事
Very well. You are commissioned to bring such an event into being.
今晚 关门一小时之后开始
Tonight. Shall we say, an hour after closing?
这是一次机会 德妮丝 证明你自己
It is an opportunity, Denise. To prove yourself.
向他们展示你真正的实力
To show to all of them what you're capable of.
不知什么时候开始你和威斯顿先生
I did not know that you and Mr Weston were
这么信任彼此了
so much in each other's confidence.
你在怀疑我的做事动机
And now you're wondering what business it is I am about.
告诉你吧 我只为天堂百货服务
Well, I shall tell you. I serve The Paradise.
你必须出类拔萃 德妮丝
You must shine, Denise.
即使是你的反对党 你也要试着人尽其才
You must persuade even the most unlikely of your colleagues
物尽其用
to take part.
你得学会白手起家的本事
You must conjure something from nothing.
你盯着我干什么
Why do you look at me?
乔纳斯先生
Mr Jonas -
你上次跳回旋舞是什么时候?
when was the last time you danced a reel?
这个嘛 一个人没办法自己跳这舞
Erm, a man cannot dance a reel alone.
况且独臂大侠可找不到舞伴
A man with one arm is no fit partner for anyone.
好吧 我有双臂双腿
Well, I have two arms and two feet,
尽管这双腿跳起舞别扭得很
although both the feet are left,
所以或许咱俩是一样的
so perhaps, overall, we'll equal each other out.
我可以唱歌! 算我一个
I can sing! Put me down.
谢了 苏西! 想想要唱的歌曲
Thank you, Susy! Have a think about the song.
遵命!
I've got it!
有人告诉我你天资非凡!
So a little birdie tells me you have a talent!
谢谢
Thank you.
山姆 我全靠你了
Sam, I'm relying on you.
你口齿伶俐
You have such a way about you.
能够让顾客好几个小时眉开眼笑的
You keep the customers entertained for hours.
你天生就是这块料!
You were born to do this!
没必要拍马屁了
There's no need to flatter us.
你知道我会为你鞠躬尽瘁的
You know I'd give you the shirt off me back.
我不用你鞠躬尽瘁 山姆
I don't want your shirt, Sam.
你只要用你那八面玲珑的才智逗人开怀就好
I only want your wit and your love of making people laugh.
此外我再加点好料怎么样
How about I throw a little something extra in there as well.
每次我要插手什么事的时候
Every time I seek to influence events,
结果总与我预期的背道而驰
the effect seems to be the perfect opposite of what I intended.
我想让她放弃 低调点
I wished her to withdraw, to be less visible,
这会儿她却绽放得更灿烂了
and she burns brighter by the moment.
还有些事没有解决
Perhaps there's something in the air.
我在教导芙罗拉 我想软化她父亲对她的态度
In teaching Flora, I hoped to soften her father towards her.
怕是会弄巧成拙
I fear the reverse may be true.
汤姆・威斯顿不吃这套
Tom Weston is not the kind of man who would love
他不爱孩子本身
the child for herself.
他只会爱她带来的荣耀
Only the reflected glory she might bring.
十先令!
Ten shillings!
我想来想去还是猜不透那是什么意思
I think and I think and still I can't fathom the meaning of it.
我奔波了好几个月
I was on the road for many months.
从未邂逅一丝善良 这儿却有千丝万缕
I met with no kindness there. And much here.
善良可不标价
It didn't come with a price tag.
可能是因为我了解被指手画脚的感觉
Perhaps I know what it is to feel judged.
曾经了解
Known.
一个人的眼界如此局限
One's borders so completely mapped that
除了眼前看到的
all around imagine
再也无法探索到更深
there is no more to you than what is seen.
没有自我
No inner self.
好吧 十先令已经相当可观了
Well, ten shillings is a considerable sum.
有它一个女人可以重新找回
A woman might find her self-respect again with that amount
自尊自重自爱
riding on her back.
虽然我觉得请我喝杯酒比较实在
Though you might just as well have bought me a drink.
你自己就可以买到杯酒
A drink is something you can buy for yourself.
想吃点什么的话 炉子上有葡萄干布丁
There's a plum duff in the stove if you've a mind.
你看起来仍然精神矍铄
You still have a spare look about you
还有 跳回旋舞的话 还是补充些能量的好
and if there's to be reeling you'll need your energy.
谁告诉你我要跳回旋舞的?
Who said anything about a reel?
隔墙有耳 乔纳斯先生
The walls have ears, Mr Jonas.
我想知道的是
What I want to know is
你会不会穿苏格兰裙上场?
will there be a kilt worn?
我对穿苏格兰裙的男人有特殊情结
I have a strange partiality for a man in a kilt.
德妮丝 据说打烊之后
Denise, it is an open secret that you are working to stage
你要在天堂百货组织一个晚会
a Music Hall, in The Paradise after closing tonight.
- 是的先生 - 威斯顿先生会出席?
- Yes, sir. - And Mr Weston is to attend?
应该会的
I believe so.
我觉得他对取消晚会的事感到遗憾
My impression is that he regretted his decision to cancel
并且希望得体地
the outing, and wishes to make reparation,
做出补偿
without losing face.
德妮丝 我在想你是不是能把这次活动
Denise, I wonder if you could find space in the programme
办得既有娱乐性又兼具教育意义
for an act that would be both entertaining and instructive.
音乐厅
- 晚上好 威斯顿夫人 - 晚上好
- Good evening, Mrs Weston. - Good evening.
- 芙罗拉. - 达德利.
- Flora. - Dudley.
可以带芙罗拉小姐看看后台吗?
Would it be OK to show Miss Flora backstage?
当然可以
Yes, of course.
芙罗拉 想去看看后台吗?
Flora, would you like to see backstage?
真是貌美如花余音绕梁啊!
You look beautiful and you sound lovely!
山姆 准备好了吗?
Sam, you ready?
他快好了! 加油山姆 最后的冲刺了
He's nearly there! Come on, Sam, just one last squeeze.
穿进去啦!
I'm in!
最好别他娘的是我想的那样
That better bloody not be what I think it is.
你不觉得模仿你也算一种奉承么?
Don't you know that imitation is a form of flattery?
欢迎来此盛会 女士们先生们 哇噢!
Welcome, ladies and gentlemen. Ooh!
你好啊 帅哥!
Hello, handsome!
现在 女士们先生们 都准备好了吗?
Now, ladies and gentlemen, are we ready for the show?
好了!
Yes!
再问一遍 都准备好了吗?
I said, are we ready for the show?
准备好了!
Yes!
下面有请...
Then I give you...
奇迹大师 亚瑟!
The Amazing Arthur!
威斯顿先生 不介意的话借用下你的帽子
Mr Weston, your hat, if you wouldn't mind.
给
There you go.
大力士 沃尔多!
The Mighty Waldo!
# 有天清晨 #
Early one morning
# 朝阳初升 #
Just as the sun was rising,
# 我听闻
I heard
年轻女孩在山谷中扬起的美妙歌声 #
a young maid singing in the valley below
# 噢 别欺骗我 #
Oh, don't deceive me
# 噢 别离开我 #
Oh, never leave me
# 你如何忍心欺侮这可怜的少女至深 #
How could you use a poor maiden so?
真不错 乔纳斯先生
That's good, Mr Jonas.
太精彩了
Bravo.
注意了 女士们先生们
Now, ladies and gentleman.
请静待我们的最终场
Please pray silence for our final act,
压轴戏来了
and the highlight of our show.
小神童 芙罗拉・威斯顿小姐!
The Infant Prodigy - Miss Flora Weston!
她要表演什么?
What is she about?
大伙们 只能问十个问题
Ladies and gentlemen, ten questions only.
我们没有多少时间了
We only have time for ten questions
所以第一个 谁先来个热场的
so that will come on a first come, first served basis.
谁呢...
So...
就你了
Yes?
请问 秘鲁的首都是?
I would like to know, what is the capital of Peru?
利马
Lima.
我想问问小神童
I would like to ask the Infant Prodigy,
"雨伞"用法语怎么说?
how do you say "umbrella" in French?
Parapluie
Parapluie.
你能说出一种化学元素吗?
Can you name me one chemical element?
铜
Copper.
北美最大的河流是?
What is the largest river in North America?
密西西比河
The Mississippi River.
你能拼出chrysanthemum(菊花)么?
Can you spell the word chrysanthemum?
C-H-R-Y-S-A-N-T-H-E-M-U-M
C-H-R-Y-S-A-N-T-H-E-M-U-M.
苏格兰的首府是?
Can you tell me the capital of Scotland?
爱丁堡
Edinburgh.
稍等一下
Excuse me?
我想问小神童一个问题
I should like to ask the Infant Prodigy a question.
克里斯多夫・哥伦布
In what year did Christopher
哪年发现新大陆的?
Columbus discover America?
1492年
1492.
她是你的荣耀
She is a credit to you.
做得好 芙罗拉小姐 来这边坐
Well done, Miss Flora, go and sit down.
感谢你们的到场 女士们先生们
Thank you all for coming, ladies and gentlemen.
今晚要特别感谢两个人 威斯顿先生
Now we have two people to thank for this evening. Mr Weston.
以及女装部的德妮丝・洛维特
And Denise Lovett of Ladieswear!
接手吧 那职位归你了
Have it. Have the job.
但我得提醒你 你会失去你男人
But I'll tell you something - you'll lose the man.
德妮丝 你惊艳了我们所有人
Denise. You have dazzled us all.
我只想惊艳到你
I only wanted to dazzle you.
我不能忍受我们分开了 我受不了
I can't bear it when we're apart. I can't bear it.
去吧 大家都等着你呢
Go. Your public awaits.
莫里 我想女装部的新主管可以定下了
Moray? I think we've found our new Head Of Ladieswear.
当心了 莫里
Only be careful, Moray.
光彩夺目的德妮丝可能会掩盖住你的光芒
Denise shines so bright she may yet outshine you.
我觉得或许你都达不到她今天的成就
I don't think even you could have achieved what she did today.
我是女装部主管
I am Head of Ladieswear.
你得尽快进入角色
You need to step into the role now.
这意味着你做的决定可能不招人喜爱
That means making decisions that others won't like.
苏西 照顾一下小姑娘
Susy, please attend to the young lady.
这些就交给你了 现在我要和莫里去喝杯咖啡
I will leave it with you while I have a coffee with Moray.
你算什么 你就是一个被宠坏了的娇娇女!
You're just a spoiled little nothing, that's what you are!
你个熊孩子!
You are a child!
苏西 到餐厅去
Susy, go down to the Refectory right now.
我要找妈妈
I want Mama.
你要为我孩子蒙受的耻辱主持公道
It was you who presided over this humiliation of my child.
你怎么处置那女孩?
What do you propose to do about this girl?
你自己想要这个职位 这不是过家家
You wanted this position. It is not all tea parties.
你得收拾东西...走人
You must collect your belongings... and go.